Guide to the Andrei Voznesenskii Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 4: Clippings
  - Subseries 4.1: About / Mentioning A.Voznesenskii
    - Subsubseries 4.1.1: Critics and Readers about A.Voznesenskii
      - Worthington, P., "TV crew couldn't disturb poet"02.16.1971, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 29, Folder 49)
        An article "TV crew couldn't disturb poet" by Peter Worthington from the newspaper "The Toronto Telegram".
        Peter Worthington.; "The Toronto Telegram".
      - Zincone, G., "Il poeta russo tenero con l'America"11.16.1971, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper (with handmade marks), damaged. (Box 29, Folder 50)
        An article "Il poeta russo tenero con l'America" by Giuliano Zincone from the newspaper "Corriere Della Sera" (in Italian).
        Giuliano Zincone.; "Corriere Della Sera".
      - Blume, M., "The Improvised Life of a Russian Poet"06.19.1972, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, severely damaged. (Box 30, Folder 1)
        An article "The Improvised Life of a Russian Poet" by Mary Blume from the newspaper "The International Herald Tribune".
        Mary Blume; Evgenii Evtushenko {Yevtushenko].; "The International Herald Tribune".
      - Dement'iev, V., "Vysokoe napriazhenie"11.12.1972, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 2)
        An article "Vysokoe napriazhenie" by Valerii Dement'iev from the newspaper "Literaturnaia gazeta".
        Valerii Dement'iev.; "Literaturnaia gazeta".
      - Lavlinskii, L., "Sedtsa vzryvnaia sila"[n.d.] 1972, A fragment of a book, 13 pages, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 3)
        Several articles from the book "Sedtsa vzryvnaia sila" by L.Lavlinskii.
        L.Lavlinskii.
      - Pomerantsev, K., "Vecher Andreia Voznesenskogo"06.15.1972, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 4)
        An article "Vecher Andreia Voznesenskogo" by K.Pomerantsev from the newspaper "Russkaia mysl' ".
        K.Pomerantsev.; "Russkaia mysl' ".
      - Shestopalov, V., Voznesenskii's photo04.01.1972, An issue of a newspaper, severely damaged. (Box 30, Folder 5)
        Voznesenskii's photo by V.Shestopalov from the newspaper "Za doblestnyi trud".
        V.Shestopalov.; "Za doblestnyi trud".
      - "Un poète sovie;tique à paris: les Francaises sont extravagantes"06.02.1972, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 6)
        An article "Un poète sovie;tique à paris: les Francaises sont extravagantes" from the newspaper "France-Soir 2" (in French).
        Roland Petit; Lilia Brik; Louis Aragon.; "France-Soir 2".
      - Wagener, F., "Entretien avec Andrei Voznesenski"; Voznesenskii, A., Wagener, F., "La poe;sie, une vitamine pour scorbutiques..."06.02.1972, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, sligthly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 7)
        An article "Entretien avec Andrei Voznesenski" by Francoise Wagener and her interview with Andrei Voznesenskii from the newspaper "Le Monde" (in French).
        Francoise Wagener.; "Le Monde".
      - About Voznesenskii in Bulgaria; Voznesenskii, A., "Zaduralski tanets", "Strela v stenata"10.09-16.1973, An issue of a newspaper with a handwritten note on the last page, sligthly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 8)
        A notice about A.Voznesenskii's visit and two Voznesenskii's poems ("Zaduralski tanets" and "Strela v stenata", trans. into Bulgarian by Andrei Germanov) from the newspaper "Studentska tribuna" (in Bulgarian). Incl. also a handwritte note from Andrei Germanov to Andrei Voznesenskii on the last page of the issue.
        Andrei Germanov.; "Studentska tribuna".
      - Gorbovskii, G., "Magnetizm Maiakovskogo"; Sevast'ianov, V. & Samoilov, A., "...Vekam, istorii i mirozdan'iu"July 1973 [?], A clipping, 3 pages, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 9)
        An article "Magnetizm Maiakovskogo" by Gleb Gorbovskii and an interview with Vitalii Sevast'ianov "...Vekam, istorii i mirozdan'iu" by Aleksei Samoilov from the literary journal "Avrora".
        Gleb Gorbovskii; Vitalii Sevast'ianov; Aleksei Samoilov; Vladimir Maiakovskii.; "Avrora".
      - Ivanova, N., "Zhadnym vzorom..."April 1973, A clipping, 3 pages, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 10)
        An article "Zhadnym vzorom..." by Natalia Ivanova from the literary journal "Znamia".
        Natalia Ivanova.; "Znamia".
      - Pankov, V., "Stikhov priroda - 'soserdtsan'ie'..."; Shklovskii, V., "Po povodu novogo sbornika Andreia Voznesenskogo"February [?] 1973, A clipping, 3 pages, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 11)
        An article "Stikhov priroda - 'soserdtsan'ie'..." by Viktor Pankov and an article "Po povodu novogo sbornika Andreia Voznesenskogo" by Viktor Shklovskii from the literary journal "Literaturnoe obozrenie" [?].
        Viktor Pankov; Viktor Shklovskii.; "Literaturnoe obozrenie" [?].
      - P'ianykh, M., "Andrei Voznesenskii. Portrety poetov"05.23.1973, A clipping with handwritten additions / corrections, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 12)
        An article "Andrei Voznesenskii. Portrety poetov" by M.P'ianykh from the newspaper "Sovetskii uchitel' ".
        M.P'ianykh.; "Sovetskii uchitel' ".
      - Voznesenskii, A., "Pokana do Roberto Obregon Morales"09.18.1973, An issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 13)
        Voznesenskii's poem in Bulgarian translation published in the newspaper "Vecherni novini".
        Roberto Obregon Morales.; "Vecherni novini".
      - Voznesenskii, A., "Sibirski bani", "Iasenite obichat", "Kazhi mi", "Zavet"09.13.1973, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 14)
        Voznesenskii's poems trans. into Bulgarian by Andrei Germanov published in the newspaper "Literaturen front".
        Andrei Germanov.; "Literaturen front".
      - Voznesenskii, A., Peikovski, I., "Poeziiata e nerv na epokhata"08.24.1973, An issue of a newspaper (probably incomplete), 3 copies, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 15)
        An interview with A.Voznesenskii from the newspaper "Otechestven front" (in Bulgarian).
        Ivan Peikovski.; "Otechestven front".
      - Zharov, A., "Kak poniat' eti stikhi?.."04.03.1973, An issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 16)
        An article "Kak poniat' eti stikhi?.." by Aleksandr Zharov from the newspaper "Vecherniaia Moskva".
        Aleksandr Zharov.; "Vecherniaia Moskva".
      - Zovtis, A., "On the problem of rhyme in the structure of modern Russian verse"1973, An offprint, 5 pages and a cover, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 17)
        An article "On the problem of rhyme in the structure of modern Russian verse" by A.Zovtis from the collection of articles "Slavic Poetics. Essays in honor of Kiril Taranovsky", 1973, Mouton, The Hague-Paris.
        A.Zovtis; Kiril Taranovsky.
      - Grigoriev, V., "Grafika i orfografiia u A.Voznesenskogo"1974, An offprint with two handwritten notes, 6 pages including a cover, severely damaged. (Box 30, Folder 18)
        An article "Grafika i orfografiia u A.Voznesenskogo" by V.P.Grigoriev from the collection of articles "Nereshennye voprosy russkogo pravopisaniia", Moscow, 1974.
        V.P.Grigoriev.
      - Soloukhin, V., "Liubitel' poezii serditsia..."05.15.1974, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 19)
        An article "Liubitel' poezii serditsia..." by Vladimir Soloukhin from the newspaper "Literaturnaia gazeta".
        Vladimir Soloukhin.; "Literaturnaia gazeta".
      - [Unknown author], On Voznesenskiin.d. [1975 ?], A clipping [?], 2 pages, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 20)
        An article on A.Voznesenskii by an unknown author.
      - Vigilianskii, V., "Piat' shestykh 'vzgliada' na 'ten' zvuka' "1975, A clipping, 6 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 21)
        An article "Piat' shestykh 'vzgliada' na 'ten' zvuka' " by Vladimir Vigilianskii from the almanach "Poeziia", #15, 1975.
        Vladimir Vigilianskii.
      - Rohde, H., "Poesie ist Instinkt"11.05.1976, A clipping, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 22)
        An article "Poesie ist Instinkt" by Hedwig Rohde from the newspaper "Der Tagesspiegel" [?] (in German).
        Hedwig Rohde.; "Der Tagesspiegel" [?].
      - Sidorow, J., "Andrej Wosnessenskis Gedichte"; Voznesenskii, A., PoetryAugust [?] 1976, A clipping, 6 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 23)
        An article "Andrej Wosnessenskis Gedichte" by Evgenii Sidorov [Jewgeni Sidorow] and several Voznesenskii's poems in Russian and German (trans. into German by Heinz Kahlau and Helmut Preissler) from the journal [?] "Sowjetliteratur" (in German).
        Evgenii Sidorov [Jewgeni Sidorow]; Heinz Kahlau; Helmut Preissler.; "Sowjetliteratur".
      - Elenkov, L., "Litse v litse s choveka-vreme"09.19.1977, An issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 24)
        An article "Litse v litse s choveka-vreme" by Luchezar [?] Elenkov from the newspaper "Pogled" (in Bulgarian).
        Luchezar [?] Elenkov.; "Pogled".
      - Georgiev, L., "Maistor na vitrazhi"06.10.1977, An issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 25)
        An article "Maistor na vitrazhi" by Liuben Georgiev from the newspaper "Sturshel" [?] (in Bulgarian).
        Liuben Georgiev.; "Sturshel" [?].
      - Georgiev, L., "Nepredotvratimite improvizatsii na Bela Akhmadulina"03.10.1977, An issue of a newspaper, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 26)
        An article "Nepredotvratimite improvizatsii na Bela Akhmadulina" by Liuben Georgiev from the newspaper "Literaturen front" (in Bulgarian).
        Liuben Georgiev; Bella Akhmadulina.; "Literaturen front".
      - Georgiev, L., "Voznesenski otblizo"; Voznesenskii, A., Poetry04.07.1977, An issue of a newspaper, 2 copies (one is incomplete), damaged. (Box 30, Folder 27)
        An article "Voznesenski otblizo" by Liuben Georgiev and several Voznesenskii's poems (trans. into Bulgarian by Dimitur [?] Vasilev) from the newspaper "Literaturen front" (in Bulgarian).
        Liuben Georgiev; Dimitur [?] Vasilev.; "Literaturen front".
      - Osnos, P., "Voznesensky, The Poet-Hero"10.27.1977, An issue of a newspaper, incomplete, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 28)
        An article "Voznesensky, The Poet-Hero" by Peter Osnos from the newspaper "The Washington Post".
        Peter Osnos.; "The Washington Post".
      - Pertsov, V., "Stikhi ne pishutsia - sluchaiutsia..."03.30.1977, An issue of a newspaper, incomplete, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 29)
        An article "Stikhi ne pishutsia - sluchaiutsia..." by V.Pertsov from the newspaper "Literaturnaia gazeta".
      - Price, A., "Russian Poet Makes Ideas, Language Sing"11.08.1977, A clipping, damaged. (Box 30, Folder 30)
        An article "Russian Poet Makes Ideas, Language Sing" by Anne Price from the newspaper "Morning Advocate".
        Anne Price.; "Morning Advocate".
      - Voznesenskii, A., "M''kite na muzata"August 1977, An issue of a journal, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 31)
        An article "M''kite na muzata" by Andrei Voznesenskii (trans. into Bulgarian by Silvia Borisova and Nikolai Kinchev [?]) from the journal "Rodna rech' ".
        Silvia Borisova; Nikolai Kinchev [?].; "Rodna rech' ".
      - Voznesenskii, A., "Pia Tvardovski sred noshchna Florentsiia..."06.10.1977, An issue of a newspaper, incomplete, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 32)
        Andrei Voznesenskii's photo and a poem (trans. into Bulgarian by Nikolai Kinchev [?]) from the newspaper "Narodna kultura".
        Aleksandr Tvardovskii; Nikolai Kinchev [?].; "Narodna kultura".
      - Voznesenskii's Photo in "Trud"09.14.1977, An issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 33)
        Andrei Voznesenskii's photo from the Bulgarian newspaper "Trud".
        "Trud".
      - Voznesenskii, A., Chatalbashev, G., "Vzaimno razbirane"09.27.1977, An issue of a newspaper, incomplete, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 34)
        An interview with Andrei Voznesenskii from the newspaper "Vecherni novini" (in Bulgarian).
        Georgi Chatalbashev.; "Vecherni novini".
      - Voznesenskii, A., Ivanov, B., "Ezik''t na izkustvoto e internatsionalen"06.07.1977, An issue of a newspaper, incomplete, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 35)
        Bogdan Ivanov.; "Vecherni novini".
      - Voznesenskii, A., Peikovski, I., "Poeziiata triabva da brani mira"09.06.1977, An issue of a newspaper (probably incomplete), slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 36)
        An interview with Andrei Voznesenskii from the newspaper "Otechestven front" (in Bulgarian).
      - Voznesenskii, A., Popov, G., "Struva mi se, che vinagi s''m bil tuk v B''lgariia"09.16.1977, An issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 37)
        An interview with Andrei Voznesenskii from the newspaper "Narodna kultura" (in Bulgarian).
        Georgi Popov.; "Narodna kultura".
      - Voznesenskii, A., Radinska, V., "Vsichko v B''lgariia e hubavo"06.08.1977, An issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 38)
        An interview with Andrei Voznesenskii from the newspaper "Narodna mladezh" (in Bulgarian).
        Valentina Radinska.; "Narodna mladezh".
      - "Zhiviiat glas na pisatelia"06.09.1977, An issue of a newspaper, 3 copies (2 of them incomplete), slightly damaged. (Box 30, Folder 39)
        A notice (with Voznesenskii's photo) from the newspaper "Literaturen front" (in Bulgarian).
        "Literaturen front".
      - "Acclaimed Russian Poet Andrei Voznesensky Recites His Works"11.03.1978, An issue of a newspaper (probably incomplete), slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 1)
        A notice (with Voznesenskii's photo) from the newspaper "The Philipian".
        "The Philipian".
      - Blume, M., "Andrei Voznesensky: Acrobat and Poet"06.10-11.1978, A clipping, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 2)
        An article "Andrei Voznesensky: Acrobat and Poet" by Mary Blume from the newspaper "International Herald Tribune".
        Mary Blume.; "International Herald Tribune".
      - Brower, M., "Poet enthralls at reading"11.17.1978, An issue of a newspaper (probably incomplete), slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 3)
        An article "Poet enthralls at reading" by Monty Brower from the newspaper "The Dartmouth".
        Monty Brower.; "The Dartmouth".
      - "Kremlin Clears Russian Poet For U.S.Encore"10.18.1978, A photocopy of a clipping, 1 page, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 4)
        A notice "Kremlin Clears Russian Poet For U.S.Encore" from the newspaper "Kansas City Times".
        "Kansas City Times".
      - Lask, Th., "Publishing: Shelf-Help"12.15.1978, A clipping, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 5)
        An article "Publishing: Shelf-Help" by Thomas Lask from the newspaper "The New York Times".
      - Lask, Th., "Words and Pictures"12.17.1978, An issue of a newspaper and two clippings, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 6)
        An article "Words and Pictures" by Thomas Lask from the newspaper "The New York Times Book Review" (3 copies).
        Thomas Lask.; "The New York Times Book Review".
      - Lemon, B., "Popularity gives poet artistic room"11.03.1978, Two identical fragments of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 7)
        An article "Popularity gives poet artistic room" by Brendan Lemon from the newspaper "The Daily Iowan" (2 copies).
        Brendan Lemon.; "The Daily Iowan".
      - McLellan, J., "From Russia With Lyricism"12.14.1978, Two identical fragments of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 8)
        An article "From Russia With Lyricism" by Joseph McLellan from the newspaper "The Washington Post" (2 copies).
        Joseph McLellan.; "The Washington Post".
      - Medina, C., "Brockport Hosts Writers Festival"10.18.1978, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 9)
        An article "Brockport Hosts Writers Festival" by Cynthia Medina from the newspaper "The Stylus".
        Cynthia Medina.; "The Stylus".
      - Miller, D., "A Poetic Interest in Reality"10.26.1978, Two fragments of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 10)
        An article "A Poetic Interest in Reality" by Donald Miller from the newspaper "Pittsburgh Post-Gazette" (2 copies).
        Donald Miller.; "Pittsburgh Post-Gazette".
      - Miller, D., "Listening to a Russian poet"11.24.1978, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper and a photocopy of a clipping with other photocopies and a note on the other side, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 11)
        An article "Listening to a Russain poet" by Margo Miller from the newspaper "The Boston Globe" (2 copies).
        Margo Miller; William Jay Smith; John Updike; Allen Ginsberg.; "The Boston Globe".
      - Mitgang, H., "Honor for Soviet Writers"11.15.1978, A clipping and a photocopy of a clipping (1 page) with a handwritten draft [?] of a poem and numerous handwritten notes on both sides of the leaf, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 12)
        An article "Honor for Soviet Writers" by Herbert Mitgang from the newspaper "The New York Times" (2 copies), a handwritten draft [?] of a poem "Gaiane" [?] (in Russian), and numerous handwritten notes.
        Herbert Mitgang; Andrei Siniavskii [Sinyavsky].; "The New York Times".
      - Ranta, J., "Soviet Poet Packs Playhouse"10.30.1978, An issue of a newspaper and a printed message, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 13)
        An article "Soviet Poet Packs Playhouse" by Judith Ranta from the newspaper "The Hunter Envoy" and a printed message from Nancy Dolensek.
        Judith Ranta; Nancy Dolensek.; "The Hunter Envoy".
      - "Russian Poet to Lecture"11.02.1978, An issue of a newspaper (probably incomplete), slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 14)
        A notice "Russian Poet to Lecture" from the newspaper "The Denver Clarion".
        "The Denver Clarion".
      - "Russian to visit GSC"10.26.1978, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 15)
        A notice "Russian to visit GSC" from the newspaper "Glassboro Whit" [?].
        "Glassboro Whit" [?].
      - Shea, R., "Poet intrigues audience"11.02.1978, A clipping, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 16)
        An article "Poet intrigues audience" by Rob Shea from the newspaper "Glassboro Whit" [?].
        Rob Shea.; "Glassboro Whit" [?].
      - Smith, L., "Packaging some striking matches"12.10.1978, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 17)
        An article "Packaging some striking matches" by Liz Smith from the newspaper "The Daily News".
        Liz Smith.; "The Daily News".
      - "The Russians are coming to BG"11.06.1978, An issue of a newspaper (probably incomplete), slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 18)
        An article "The Russians are coming to BG" from the newspaper "The Green Sheet".
        "The Green Sheet".
      - "The Second Annual SUNY Writers Festival"November 1978, An issue of a newspaper (probably incomplete), slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 19)
        An article "The Second Annual SUNY Writers Festival" from the newspaper "The News".
        "The News".
      - Thompson, H., "Poetasters"12.11.1978, A clipping, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 20)
        A notice "Poetasters" by Howard Thompson from the newspaper "The New York Times".
        Howard Thompson.; "The New York Times".
      - Voznesenskii, A., "Guyana"12.02.1978, Two fragments of an issue of a newspaper and a clipping with a handwritten mark, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 21)
        A poem "Guyana" by Andrei Voznesenskii (trans. into English by William Jay Smith and Vera Dunham) from the newspaper "The New York Times", 3 copies.
        William Jay Smith; Vera Dunham.; "The New York Times".
      - Voznesenskii, A., "Maistori"Oct [?] 1978, A fragment of an issue of a journal, 4 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 22)
        A poem "Maistori" by Andrei Voznesenskii (trans. into Bulgarian by Andrei Germanov) from the journal "Plam''k" [?].
        Andrei Germanov.; "Plam''k" [?].
      - Voznesenskii, A., "Shest' variatsii na temy Uil'iama Dzheia Smita"10.04.1978, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper with a handwritten note, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 23)
        An article "Shest' variatsii na temy Uil'iama Dzheia Smita" by Andrei Voznesenskii and six poems by William Jay Smith (trans. into Russian by Andrei Voznesenskii) from the newspaper "Literaturnaia gazeta".
        William Jay Smith.; "Literaturnaia gazeta".
      - Voznesenskii's Award11.07.1978, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, sligthly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 24)
        A notice "O prisuzhdenii Gosudarstvennykh premii SSSR 1978 goda v oblasti literatury, iskusstva i arkhitektury" by Leonid Brezhnev and Andrei Kosygin from the newspaper "Pravda".
        Leonid Brezhnev; Andrei Kosygin.; "Pravda".
      - Whitney, C.R., "Voznesensky Regains Poetic Crown"; [No author] "Internationally Acclaimed Russia's Greatest Modern Poet"05.22.1978, A photocopy of a clipping, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 25)
        An article "Voznesensky Regains Poetic Crown" by Craig R. Whitney and a notice "Internationally Acclaimed Russia's Greatest Modern Poet" from the newspaper "The New York Times".
        Craig R. Whitney.; "The New York Times".
      - Kanfer, S., "Periscope of The Buried Dead"01.15.1979, A fragment of an issue of a magazine, 3 pages, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 26)
        An article "Periscope of The Buried Dead" by Stefan Kanfer and several notices from the magazine "Time".
        Stefan Kanfer.; "Time".
      - The New York Review About Russian Black Market05.31.1979, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper with a handwritten mark, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 27)
        An article about Russian black market (the beginning is missing) from the newspaper "The New York Review".
        "The New York Review".
      - Voznesenskii about Bulgarian and Russian culturies[n.d.] 1979, Two identical fragments of an issue of a journal (one with a handwritten note), 2 pages total, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 28)
        A small notice about Bulgarian and Russian culturies by A.Voznesenskii from the journal "Obzor" (2 copies).
        Bella Akhmadulina; Elisaveta Bagriany; Georgii Dzhagarov; Liubomir Levchev; Bozhidar Bozhilov.; "Obzor".
      - Wainstein, L., "Il disgelo su Pasternak, lo scomunicato"09.20.1980, A photocopy of a clipping with several handwritten notes, 1 page, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 29)
        An article "Il disgelo su Pasternak, lo scomunicato" by Lia Wainstein from the newspaper "La Stampa" [?] (in Italian).
        Lia Wainstein; Boris Pasternak.; "La Stampa" [?].
      - Whitney, C.R., "Pasternak Recalled in Glory and Disgrace"09.20-21.1980, A photocopy of a clipping with a handwritten note, 1 page, damaged. (Box 31, Folder 30)
        An article "Pasternak Recalled in Glory and Disgrace" by Craig R. Whitney from the newspaper "International Herald Tribune" [?].
        Craig R. Whitney; Boris Pasternak.; "International Herald Tribune" [?].
      - Blume, M., "Russian Poet on a Tightrope"03.11.1981, A fragment of an issue of a newspaper, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 31)
        An article "Russian Poet on a Tightrope" by Mary Blume from the newspaper "International Herald Tribune".
        Mary Blume; Boris Pasternak.; "International Herald Tribune".
      - Forrest, A., "Poetry Olympics"12.07.1981, A photocopy of a clipping with a handwritten note, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 32)
        An article "Poetry Olympics" by Alan Forrest from the newspaper "The Financial Times" [?].
        Alan Forrest.; "The Financial Times" [?].
      - Horovitz, M., "Poetry and Literature"12.19.1981, A photocopy of a clipping with several handwritten marks, 1 page, slightly damaged. (Box 31, Folder 33)
        An article "Poetry and Literature" by Michael Horovitz from the newspaper [?] "New Musical Express".
        Michael Horovitz.; "New Musical Express".